你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because...I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行是无关信息
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner.
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
不管是被害人还是行凶者  只要你的号码被列出来
But victim or perpetrator, if your number's up,
我们就会找到你
we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第18集
Person of Interest S01E18 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
早上好  里瑟先生
Good morning, Mr. Reese.
借你吉言
If you say so.
里面是croquillants吗
Any croquillants in there?
法文甜点名
如果你是指甜甜圈  答案是有
If that's a doughnut, then yes.
有什么事儿
So what do we got?
不太走运  信息不多
Nothing much, unfortunately.
机器吐出了一个号码
The machine kicked out a number that has
这号码的网络痕迹少得前所未见
one of the smallest digital footprints I've never seen.
没照片吗
No photos?
并不是每个纽约人都有驾照  里瑟先生
Not everyone in New York has a driver's license, Mr. Reese.
社保号码前三位表明
First three digits of the social
乔丹・海丝特出生于乔治亚州
suggest that Jordan Hester was born in Georgia.
难道要我凭借口音认出他吗
I'm supposed to recognize him by his accent?
或者是她  我甚至都没法辩明性别
Or her. I can't even verify the gender.
海丝特的生活远离因特网  网上没有照片
Hester's living off the grid-- no photos online
社交网站也难觅其踪
and nothing on the social networking sites.
真不理解人们干嘛
Never understood why people
要把个人信息发到那些网站上
put all their information on those sites.
这可为我之前在中情局的工作大开方便之门
Used to make our job a lot easier in the CIA.
这是自然  所以我才建了那些东西
Of course. That's why I created them.
你是说  是你发明了社交网站吗  芬奇
You're telling me you invented online social networking, Finch?
机器需要更多的信息
The machine needed more information.
人们的社交关系  他们之间的联系
People's social graph, their associations--
政府多年来一直在试图弄清楚这些
The government had been trying to figure it out for years.
结果大多数人都自愿贡献出来
Turns out most people were happy to volunteer it.
商家也籍此获得巨额利润
Business wound up being quite profitable too.
很不幸  乔丹・海丝特似乎
Unfortunately, Jordan Hester seems
比大多数人要谨慎
to be more cautious than most.
不过我还是能做个信用调查
But I was able to run a credit check.
结果显示  海丝特各方各面都有两个
According to this, Hester's got two of everything.
两个银行账户  两套公寓
Two bank accounts, two apartments,
-两份电话账单  -如果非要我猜
- two phone bills. - If I had to guess,
你也知道我很讨厌猜测
which, as you know, I hate doing,
我得说咱们要找的是个有着双重身份的人
I'd say we're looking at a person leading a double life.
一个人搞不定
Can't cover them both.
你该出去呼吸新鲜空气了
Time for you to get some fresh air.
我给卡特打电话
I'll call Carter,
看看咱们要找的人有没有犯罪记录
see if our guy--or girl-- has a criminal record.
你确定这样好吗
Is that a good idea?
卡特警官现在可不太待见你
Detective Carter's not exactly your number one fan right now
瞧瞧  卡特警探
Lo and behold, Detective Carter
亲临现实中的凶案调查现场
at an actual homicide investigation.
怎么  追那个神秘男人追烦了吗
What, are you tired of chasing around your mystery man?
有什么发现
What do we got?
男性非裔  17岁
African-American male, 17 years old.
送到医院前已死亡  多亏了这些天才们
DOA, thanks to this genius over here.
他们因为一个女孩起了争执
They got into an argument over a girl.
-杀人凶手  -但事实已经清楚了
- Murderer! - But this is open and closed.
-这孩子已经招认了  -他有说动机吗
- The kid already confessed. - Did he say why he did it?
他的原话是"我还能怎么办"
He said, and I quote, "What was I supposed to do?"
然后又说  这都是我们的错
And then he said it was our fault.
这话什么意思
Yeah, how does that follow?
怪我们没赶来阻止他
Said we weren't here to stop him.
等我一会儿
One second.
好的
Sure.
未知号码
我试图阻止他
I tried to stop it.
可是无能为力
There was nothing I could do.
我在上城区的公寓里  里瑟先生
I'm at the apartment in the Village, Mr. Reese.
-你在布鲁克林的公寓吗  -是的
- Are you at the one in Brooklyn? - Yep.
有任何有关海丝特的线索吗
Any sign of Hester at your location?
要是知道我要找的是什么就好了
It would help if I knew what I was looking for.
您好
Hello.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you so much.
谁后进入  中午请客
Last one in pays for lunch.
我想吃印度菜
I'm in the mood for Indian.
卡特警官那边有回复吗
Any response from Detective Carter?
还是不接我电话
Still not answering my calls.
也许应该换你试试
Maybe you should try her.
卡特的意见不是针对你  里瑟先生
You know, Carter's issue isn't with you, Mr. Reese,
而是针对你的方法
It's with your methods...
我们的方法
Our methods.
更别提
Not to mention the fact
你供出了她负责保护的证人
that you gave up a witness under her protection
还差点害死一名警察
and nearly got a cop killed in the process.
-人孰无过嘛  芬奇  -波西米亚风格
- Nobody's perfect, Finch. - This is very bohemian.
也许海丝特是名艺术家或作家
Maybe Hester's an artist or writer.
但没有照片
No photos though.
你看到什么了
What are you seeing?
斯巴达风格
Well...It's very Spartan.
只有一张桌子  一个床垫
Just a desk, mattress,
一些健身器材  基本上就这些
Some free weights. Not much else.
也许那是海丝特的办公室
Maybe it's Hester's office.
在不同的公寓楼里吗
In a different apartment building?
发现一卷钱  上面标有海丝特首字母缩写
Found a money roll marked with Hester's initials.
但都是小面额
Mostly small bills though.
我在检查垃圾  发现了一些收据
Just going through his garbage. I got some receipts.
"锤与钉"
The Hammer And Nail.
这酒吧就在拐角那边
That pub is just around the corner from here.
收据显示享有员工折扣
Receipt shows an employee discount.
这钱可能是小费
Money could be from a tip pool.
芬奇  我要去查查
Finch, I'm going to check it out.
如果他居住工作都在布鲁克林
If he lives and works in Brooklyn,
那这地方又是用来干嘛的
what's this place for?
-要点什么  -随便弄点现成的
- What can I get ya? - Whatever's on tap.
海丝特  怎么搞了这么久
Hester, what's taking you so long?
这些被压在一堆箱子下面
They were under a bunch of other boxes.
芬奇  我看到海丝特了
Finch, got eyes on Hester.
-他在酒吧做服务员  -服务员
- He's working as a barback. - Barback?
他怎么付得起两套房子的租金
How can he afford to keep up the rent on both places?
多谢您的帮助
Thanks for all the help.
没什么
Yeah, well--
今天可比昨天暖和多了
It's much warmer than yesterday.
是啊是啊  好了
I know, I know. Okay.
还有什么要帮忙的吗  海丝特小姐
So anything else I can do for you, Miss Hester?
没有了  我说最后一次  雷
No, and for the last time, Ray,
请叫我乔丹就好
Please call me Jordan.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese...
你看到海丝特了  但我听到海丝特了
You have eyes on Hester, but I have ears on her.
-什么  -乔丹・海丝特
- What? - Jordan Hester.
现在正在她的公寓里
She's here in her apartment.
这根本就不是什么以双重身份生活的人
This isn't one person leading a double life.
是两个人以同一身份生活
It's two people living one.
欢迎回家
Welcome back.
我看我得感谢你
I suppose I should thank you
帮我疏散了那栋大厦
for making them evacuate the building.
要谢就谢自动喷水灭火系统
Thank the automatic sprinkler system.
我们还是不知道乔丹・海丝特是什么人
So we still have no idea who Jordan Hester is.
至少我们把范围缩小了
Well, at least we narrowed it down.
两个人共享一个社保号码
Two people, one social security number,
只有一个是真正的海丝特
only one can be Hester,
另外一个肯定是冒牌货
so someone is an imposter.
祝你能够成功找出来
Good luck telling who's who.
咱们得赶紧弄清楚
We'd better decide quickly.
通常机器吐给我们一个号码后
Usually when the machine gives us a number,
只有24到48小时阻止事情发生
we have only 24 to 48 hours before something happens.
我们不是应该能找到
Shouldn't we be able to track down
他们其中某人的出生证明吗
a birth certificate for one of them?
很早之前的出生证明很难弄到
Long-form birth certificates are hard to get a hold of.
大多数20年以上的医疗记录
Most medical records over 20 years old
都没有被数字化
aren't digitized anywhere.
我们面对的不是一般的身份盗窃  对吧
We're not dealing with a typical identity thief here, are we
确实不是
No.
那种人通常会偷了你的钱
Normally they would steal your money
然后拿去挥霍
and go on a shopping spree.
这个偷的可是全部的生活
This one is stealing a whole life.
那女人的手提电脑里有发现吗
Did you get anything from the woman's laptop?
邮件和联系人表  没有任何迹象显示
Emails and contact list-- nothing that would indicate
她不是真正的乔丹・海丝特
that she's not the real Jordan Hester.
我侵入了那男人的电话
I blue-jacked our guy's phone,
检查了他的最近通话记录
went through his recent calls.
看来他上星期租了辆货车
Seems he rented a van la week.
也许他总算决定要去买点家具了
Maybe he's finally going to buy some furniture.
两个人都得盯着
We'll need to keep eyes on both of them
直到搞清楚为止
till we figure this out.
我们还是需要外援
We're still going to need an extra hand.
真正的乔丹・海丝特  请上前一步
Will the real Jordan Hester please stand up?
你好啊  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
把莫雷蒂拱手让给了以利亚  有你的
Nice job handing Moretti over to Elias.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
你要HR的动静  不用担心了
Well, you got HR buzzing. Don't worry about it though.
我快查出幕后主脑们了
I'm pretty close to finding out who the major players are.
我叫你来不是问HR的事情
I didn't ask you here to talk about HR.
有任务给你
I've got an assignment for you.
我要你去查关于乔丹・海丝特的一切
I need you to dig up everything you can on a Jordan Hester.
你要我去HR卧底
You got me doing undercover work for HR.
现在又要我做"伟光正"的活儿
Now you want me to do above-the-board stuff too?
你到底要我怎么样
Make up your mind.
我的工作可不是包你轻松混日子  莱奈尔
I didn't realize it was my job To make yours easier, Lionel
一会儿好警察  一会儿坏警察
Hey, good cop, bad cop,
你在拿我的生活当儿戏耍
It's only my life we're playing with here.
我才不管你的生活呢  是吧
It's not your life I'm focused on right now, is it?
有人需要我们的帮助
Someone needs our help.
-哪一位  -就是要你查清这点
- Which one? - Exactly.
我尽力吧
I'll see what I can do.
芬奇  你跟的海丝特如何了
Hey, Finch, what's your Hester up to?
六个小时了  尽在跑腿儿了
Six hours and all she's done is run errands.
接下来好像要去邮局
Probably go to the post office next.
-我跟的这位海丝特还在工作  -这么说
- My Hester's still at work. - So we're dealing with
我们跟的是地球上最平凡的两个人了
the two most ordinary people on the planet.
偏偏其中一个名不符实
Except one of them is not what they seem.
我又研究了一下那份信用报告
I did some more digging on that credit report,
发现很有趣的一点
found something interesting.
上城西区的一处豪华公寓
A luxury co-op on the upper West Side
六个月前做了一份信用调查
ordered a credit check six months ago.
也许值得一看
Might be worth a look.
你不是说还有第三个乔丹・海丝特吧
You're not telling me there's a third Jordan Hester, are you
我想没有
I don't think so.
其中一位海丝特在那里租了一间大公寓
One of our Hesters rented a large apartment there.
但前台说他从没见过任何一位海丝特
But the man at the front desk says he's never met him or her
我跟的这海丝特还在上班呢
Well, my Hester's still in the middle of his shift.
我去查查
I'll check it out.
你没跟双尸命案吗
You pull a double homicide?
在帮一个朋友跟个案子
I'm just doing a favor for a friend over at vice.
你以前办过身份盗窃案吗
Did you ever work an identity theft case?
每个案件都是
Every arrest I ever made.
所有被捕的人都说我抓错人了
They all say I got the wrong guy.
帮忙那些还活着的人  感觉一定很好
Must be nice, helping out people who are still alive.
一切还好吧
Everything okay?
卡特警探  我是唐纳利特工
Detective Carter. I'm Special Agent Donnelly.
我们上月在德兰西枪击案中合作过
We worked together on the Delancey shooting last month.
是的  什么风把你吹来了
Right, of course. What brings you back to the "A"?
实际上  就是你
You, actually.
什么事情
What's this about?
数月前你把一套指纹输入了自动指纹识别系统
You sent a set of fingerprints through AFIS a few months back
我在凶案组工作  这很正常
I work homicide. That tends to happen.
没错  这个引起了我们的注意
Yeah, well, these got our attention.
你的报告中
In your reports,
你称他为"西装男"
you refer to him as "the man in the suit."
我们认为  就是这个人攻击了我们
We think this may be the same man who assaulted my team
绑架了我们监管中的嫌犯
and kidnapped a suspect in our custody.
在我印象中
The way I remember it,
那个嫌犯之后洗净了全部嫌疑
the suspect was later cleared of all charges.
这不是重点  警探
That's beside the point, Detective.
目前  我们以为此人涉嫌
Now our agents believe that this man may be connected to
数年来的多宗谋杀及袭击悬案
dozens of unsolved homicides and assaults over the years,
其中相当一部分发生在最近六个月的纽约
Many of them here in New York in the last six months.
涉及退役军人的连环银行抢劫案
A series of bank robberies involving ex-military,
杀害前东德特务
Killing of a Stasi operative,
枪击毒贩  黑帮教父  甚至警察
shootings of drug dealers, gangsters, even police officers.
现在  据你推测
Now, you speculated,
根据你对此人的初步调查
based on your initial interview with this man,
他是退役军人  可能是前特种部队的
that he was former military, maybe special forces.
全在我的报告里了
It's all in my reports.
不不  没全
No. No, it's not.
远远没全
Not by a long shot.
什么时候抽一小时跟我聊聊  警察
When can you spare me an hour, detective?
我有东西给你看
I've got something to show you.
需要帮忙吗
Can I give you a hand with that?
-谢谢  -给我吧
- Thank you. - There you are.
我去查看三楼的公寓  芬奇
I'm taking a look at this third apartment, Finch.
查找任何能让我们确定是哪位海丝特的线索
Look for anything that might point to which Hester it belongs to
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time.
必须查出威胁来自何处
We need to find out where the threat's coming from.
不知道是哪位海丝特的
Don't know which Hester it belongs to,
不过我知道他们在做什么了
But I got an idea what they're mixed up in.
我置身在二亚甲基双氧苯丙胺实验室中
I'm standing in the middle of an MDMA lab.
摇头丸  你确定吗
Ecstasy. Are you sure?
不然的话  就是有人痴迷化学
Well, it's either that or someone's really into chemistry.
找到个能告诉我们实情的人
Found a guy who can tell us what's going on.
不过他一时半会儿没法说话
But he's not really in a talking mood right now.
看来我要有别的同伴了
Looks like I'm going to have more company soon.
-喂  -再会
- Hello? - Good-bye.
至少我们知道冒名者为何盗用海丝特的身份了
At least we know why our I.D. thief stole Hester's name.
摇头丸可以用合法的化学品合成
MDMA can be made with legal chemicals,
不过这些药剂是被监测的  一旦大批购入
But they're monitored. Buy in bulk,
就会引起当局的注意
and you draw the attention of the authorities.
但是如果你借用了别人的名字
But if you use someone else's name...
他们就束手无策了
They wind up holding the bag.
看来不只是你那位海丝特有工作
Looks like your Hester's not the only one who's employed.
乔丹的邮件表明她在古董店工作
Jordan's emails indicate that she works in antiques,
也许是采购员  或是经销商
Maybe as a buyer or a dealer.
乔丹
"Jordan"?
你们的关系已经亲密到直呼其名了吗
Are you on a first name basis already?
没有  我只是  讨厌用代称
No, I'm just... tired of using pronouns.
芬奇  我们的制毒者醒了
Hey, Finch, our ecstasy cook just woke up.
-怎么回事  -有人闯入
- What happened? - Some guy broke in.
-把我打晕了  -东西都没丢
- Got the drop on me. - Well, he didn't take anything.
我们现在有更严重的问题
We got a bigger problem right now.
-老大想见你  -什么
- The boss wants to meet. - What?
四年来我们从没见过老大
Four years and we've never even seen the boss.
-为什么现在忽然想见我  -不知道
- Why are we meeting him now? - I don't know.
肯定不是好事
This can't be good.
走吧  见面安排在一小时后
Come on, meeting's in an hour.
公寓租约上有海丝特的名字
Hester's name is on the lease for that co-op.
差别在于  老大是你那位海丝特还是我这位
Odds are, either your Hester or mine is the boss.
我们得跟紧点  芬奇
We need to stay close, Finch.
天  我想我跟丢她了
Dear. I think I just lost her.
有时我想要是他今天发表
Sometimes I wonder if he'd be published today.
《审判》
弗兰兹・卡夫卡
那我肯定第一个排队买
I'd be first in line,
不过  我的腿脚不太容易抢到首名
but then, meandering exposition is kind of my thing.
抱歉  我无意冒犯
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to intrude.
没有  这个  我叫哈罗德
No, that's-- I'm Harold.
我叫乔丹
Jordan.
失陪一下
Excuse me a moment.
你干嘛给我打电话
Why are you calling me?
你干嘛跟她聊天
Why are you talking to her?
因为我没有你那种隐形藏身的本领
Because I haven't your gift for avoiding people.
再说  她挺和善的
Besides, she seems nice,
而且对文学的品味很高
And she has excellent taste in literature.
又或者她发现了你在尾随她
Or she knows you're tailing her,
于是转回头来反戈一击
and she circled back for a closer look.
玛吉  我走啦  明天见
Maggie, I'm taking off. I'll see you tomorrow.
芬奇  海丝特行动了
Finch, Hester's on the move.
他可能要跟制毒者会面
He could be meeting up with the cooks.
我又跟丢她了
I've lost her again.
里瑟先生  你说的那个制毒者长什么样子
Mr. Reese, what did that drug cook look like?
是不是大块头  有点吓人
Big, kind of...terrifying?
绝对不是
Not even close.
如果我们错把这位女士当成了毒贩
If we've mistaken this woman for a drug dealer,
别人是不是也会这么想
isn't it possible that someone else has too?
一切皆有可能  芬奇
Anything's possible, Finch.
你带武器了吗
Did you bring a weapon?
我说过了  里瑟先生  我不喜欢武器
I told you, Mr. Reese. I don't like weapons.
那你就准备靠一张嘴说死他们吧
Well, you'd better be prepared to talk them to death,
还得快点儿
and you'd better do it fast,
因为我已经知道谁是冒名者了
Because I think I know which one of them is the imposter,
也就是说  你跟着的海丝特有麻烦了
which means your Hester is in trouble.
乔丹
Jordan!
你的外套忘了拿
You forgot your jacket.
你有危险  跟我走
You're in danger. Come with me.
那些是什么人
Who were those guys?
别回头  继续走
Don't look back. Just keep walking.
-你就是老大  -没错  是我
- So you're the boss? - Yeah, that's right.
别误会我的意思
Don't take this the wrong way,
但我们为什么要见面
but why are we meeting in person?
有人盯上我们了
Someone's onto us.
我们得弄完这批  马上转移
We need to finish this batch and relocate.
-黄樟醚不够了  -已经搞定了
- We're low on safrole. - Already got it covered.
看来我们弄清楚谁是谁了
Looks like we know who's who.
我这位是毒贩
My guy's the drug dealer.
而你那位毒贩
And your drug dealer has placed
将真正的乔丹・海丝特置于险境了
the real Jordan Hester in danger.
好了  快点  我们走吧
All right, come on. Hurry up. Let's go.
你好  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
我看你那家伙是在制毒
Hey, I think your guy might be cooking ecstasy.
是吗
Is that so?
他六个月前被捕了
He got arrested six months ago
当时他一个下线被警方端了
when one of his distributors got popped.
毒品署有证据证明他在买化学品
Narcotics found evidence that he was buying chemicals,
但毒贩没办法指认他
But the distributor couldn't pick him out of a lineup,
所以他们只能放走海丝特
So they had to cut Hester loose.
毒贩只知道一个名字
All the distributor knew was a name.
他从没真正见过老大
He had actually never met the boss.
就这些了
So if that's it,
我现在能专心只为你打一份工了吧
then maybe I can just go back to doing one job for you, huh?
还不行
Not just yet.
海丝特  管他叫什么名字
Hester-- or whatever his name is--
反正非常在意保护自己的身份
is very serious about protecting his identity.
也许在意到会为此杀人灭口
Maybe serious enough to kill.
你觉得他会找上那姑娘吗
You think he'd go after the girl?
这正是我要知道的
That's what I need to know,
也正意味着你要查出
which means you need to find out
他是怎么偷她身份的
how he stole her identity.
那些人是谁
But who were those guys?
恐怕他们都是毒贩
I'm afraid they may be in the drug trade,
而且认为你也是
and they think you are too.
谢谢
Thanks.
这就是偷我身份的人吗  毒贩
That's who stole my identity? A drug dealer?
你知道自己身份被盗了
So you know about the I.D. Theft.
我知道几个星期了
I've known for a few weeks,
但我觉得已经被盗好几个月了
but I think it's been going on for months.
我一直在给我的信用卡公司和银行打电话
I kept calling my credit card company, my bank.
他们一直叫我报警
They kept telling me to call the police.
警察却一直叫我填各种报告
The cops just kept telling me to fill out more reports
然后给银行打电话
and call the bank.
白领犯罪总是不被
White collar crime is at the bottom
任何警察部门所重视
of every police department's to-do list.
这么说你不是警察
Well, I take it you're not a cop.
不算
Not quite.
哈罗德・克劳
私家侦探
Private investigator?
有点推理小说家雷蒙德・钱德勒的感觉  是吗
It's very Raymond Chandler, isn't it
但恐怕现实会有些乏味
The reality is a little bit more mundane, I'm afraid,
大部分时间只是跟踪和拍照
Mostly following people around and taking pictures.
你为什么要跟踪我
Why were you following me?
另一个受害者雇的我
I've been hired by another victim.
警方同样没有为他做任何事
The police didn't do anything for him either.
-那我现在该怎么做  -现在吗
- So what do I do now? - Right now?
深呼吸  来杯茶
Breathe deep. Have a cup of tea.
有人在帮我跟踪
I have someone keeping an eye
偷你身份的人
on the man that stole your identity.
只要我们一有足够证据逮捕他
As soon as we have enough proof to arrest him,
就可以请警方介入了
we'll get the police involved.
富兰克林吗
You Franklin?
你一定就是弗斯科了
You must be Fusco.
德茨・富兰克林警探  身份盗窃小组的
Detective Dez Franklin, I.D. Theft Squad.
有什么可以效劳的
How can I help?
乔丹・海丝特  我们的受害者
Jordan Hester, she's our vic.
男人盗用女人的身份  这倒新鲜
A man stealing a woman's identity--that's a new one.
是啊  似乎已经用了一年了
Yeah, apparently, it's been going on for about a year now.
一年了  这么说不是为血拼大采购
A year? So we're not talking about a shopping spree at Best Buy.
他在用她的身份为犯罪活动做掩护  是吗
He's using her I.D. as a cover for criminal activity, right?
-我们认为他在生产摇头丸  -不是吧
- We think he's cooking E. - Seriously?
有什么不对的地方
Why do you find that so strange?
去年有个案子
This case last year.
嫌犯在整个审讯阶段都坚持自己是无辜的
Suspect claimed he was innocent all the way through trial,
说有人盗用了他的身份
said somebody stole his identity.
没人相信他吗
No one believed him?
我的部门每天会抓进来一百多个嫌疑犯
My unit catches upwards of 100 new complaints every day.
不能谁说自己无辜我们都相信吧
Can't bring us in every time somebody says he didn't do it.
-罪名是什么  -意图制造毒品
- What was the charge? - Manufacture with intent.
制摇头丸
Making ecstasy.
凯尔・莫里森
Kyle Morrison.
我确定他还在狱中
I'm pretty sure he's still locked up.
我来结账
I'll take this.
该我上场了
That's my cue.
我是富兰克林警探
I'm Detective Franklin.
我想就一系列信用卡盗窃事件和你谈谈
I'd like to talk to you about a string of credit card thefts
我们已经发现你围裙下的扫描仪了
We already know about the scanner you keep under your apron.
-纽约凶案组  -你好  我是弗斯科警探
- NYPD homicide. - Yes, it's Detective Fusco.
我想查一名叫凯尔・莫里森的囚犯
I'm looking for an inmate by the name of Kyle Morrison.
能告诉我他被关在哪里吗
Can you tell me where he's being held?
我查一下
Let me see that.
希望你用茶还愉快  芬奇
Hope you're enjoying your tea, Finch.
我准备上前检查一下海丝特的货车
I'm going to take a closer look at Hester's van.
这家伙上哪儿都带着他的电脑
The guy takes his computer with him everywhere.
他甚至比你还谨慎  芬奇
He's even more careful than you are, Finch.
我大概需要你帮忙解开他的
I might need a little help cracking his--
不必了
Never mind.
笔记本没设密码
Laptop's not password-protected.
看来他没我想得那么谨慎  芬奇
Guess he's not as careful as I thought, Finch.
好吧  没看到任何贩毒盈利的秘密账户
Okay, not seeing any secret accounts full of drug profits
也没关于贩毒的信息
or messages about business.
能给你更多筹码  有效掌控
To give you more leverage and control--
贩毒老手什么时候开始
And since when do seasoned drug dealers
需要从网上查找"须知"了
need how-to tips from the internet?
我错过了一场客户会议
I missed a client meeting.
你靠什么谋生的
What do you do for a living?
严格说来  我是自由职业买家
Well, technically I'm a freelance buyer,
但没人明白那是干嘛的
but no one really knows what that means.
-买什么的  -古董
- Buyer of what? - Antiques.
我喜欢有历史的东西
You know, I love old stuff.
-比如书  -特别是书
- Like books. - Especially books.
我买不起我喜欢的东西
I can't really afford to buy the stuff I like,
所以别人雇我  我就帮他们买古董
so people hire me and I buy old stuff for them.
有点像住狗窝的室内设计师
Kind of like a interior decorator with cobwebs.
听上去很有意思
Sounds like fun.
用艺术学位做这个  有点丢人
Well, it's an embarrassing use of an arts degree,
但这是我的梦想
but it's my dream.
我希望有天能有一家自己的店
You know, someday I'd love to own my own shop.
当然前提是  这身份被盗的事
That is, if this whole I.D. thing
别永远地毁掉我的信用记录
hasn't permanently ruined my credit,
否则就至死方休了
or I don't wind up dead.
知道我什么时候可以回家吗
Any idea when I can go home?
我觉得现在太危险了
I think it's too dangerous right now.
万一那帮人查到了你家地址怎么办
What if these guys figured out where you live?
我们会给你找间酒店
We should get you a hotel room.
我能不能至少回去收点东西
Can I at least pack a bag?
我不认为这是明智之举
I'm not sure that's wise.
就算你陪着我也不行吗
Even if you came with me?
这就是下次全部的货吗
So this is our entire next shipment?
你上哪儿弄的这个  闻上去有点不一样
Where'd you get this stuff? It smells a little different.
因为这次纯度更高
That's because it's even more pure.
快开始做
Now let's start the cook.
那这批货弄好要多长时间
So this batch will be ready in, what?
24小时吗
24 hours or so?
你当是我奶奶煮饭呢
If my nana was cooking it.
你是凶案组的吗
You're homicide?
你们觉得我还杀了人吗
You guys think I killed someone too?
这不是我此行的目的
That's not why I'm here.
所以你只是想过来戳我痛处吗
What, so you just want to rub it in?
那么  恭喜你  你做到了
Well, congratulations. You got me.
我觉得你没做
I thought you didn't do it.
我不是毒贩
I'm not a drug dealer.
多年来我一直这么说
I've been saying that for a year.
但没人肯相信我
Nobody's believed me yet.
一次是贼  终生是贼
Once a suspect, always a suspect.
这不是纽约警察的官方座右铭吗
Isn't that the official NYPD motto?
你第一次何时意识到自己的身份被盗
When did you know your identity was first stolen?
当警察来敲我家门
When the cops knocked down my door,
拿枪顶着我脑袋的时候
put a shotgun to my head.
那是什么时候  一年前吧
And that was what? A year ago?
要我说
You know what?
跟你们这帮人说的越多
The more I talked to you guys,
你们越能扭曲我的话
the more you twisted my words around.
所以  我今天大概没心情说话
So, you know, maybe today I'm not in the mood.
我们觉得发生在你身上的事
We think what happened to you
可能在别人身上重演了
may have happened to someone else.
坐下
Sit down.
我知道你没理由相信我
Look, I know you got no reason to trust me.
我很明白你的感受
I know exactly how you feel.
每个人都误解了你
Everyone's got you wrong.
每个人都冤枉了你
Everyone thinks you're something that you're not,
而你却没法改变他们的想法
And you got no way to change their mind.
你帮我抓住这家伙
You help me catch this guy,
我想办法把你弄出去
and I'll see about getting you out of here.
你相信我吗
You believe me?
除非让我无法相信
Until you give me reason not to.
在  在一开始  只是钱有问题
When it--when it started, it was just the money.
我打给银行  他们就关闭了账户
I'd call the bank, and then they'd close the account,
然后立马又有一个账户冒了出来
but then another one would pop right back up.
很快  我的信用纪录完了
Before long, my credit was shot,
存款没了
my savings were gone.
没法还贷款  没法养家
Couldn't pay my mortgage. I couldn't support my family.
然后警察就出现了
And then the cops came rolling up.
你有孩子吗
You got kids?
我儿子九岁了
My boy's nine.
上个月错过了我女儿的两岁生日
Missed my daughter's second birthday last month.
她妈妈再也不想和我有任何交集了
Her mother doesn't want anything to do with me anymore.
你帮我抓住这家伙
Look, you help me catch this guy,
我将尽我所能让你回家见你的宝贝女儿
and I'll do my best to get you home and see your little girl
我向你保证
I give you my word.
有点不对劲
Something's not right here.
见鬼  我们没时间了
Damn it, we're out of time.
警察已经在过来的路上了
The cops are on their way here right now.
什么  怎么会
What? How?
管它为什么  我们得赶快把成品运走
Who cares? We've gotta get this merch out of here fast.
那制毒怎么办
What about the cook?
别管它了  这实验室完蛋了
Forget it, this lab is burned.
把指纹都擦干净  我把东西装起来
Wipe everything down for prints. I'm gonna pack this stuff up
没有危险
It's okay.
太好了
Oh, okay.
为什么到处都是毛巾
Why are there towels everywhere?
是啊  自动喷水灭火系统昨天启动了
Yeah, sprinkler system went off yesterday.
-某个傻瓜触发了火警  -真奇怪
- Some idiot pulled the alarm. - How odd.
我替你订好了一间酒店
I've arranged a hotel room for you,
如果你想收拾一下东西
if you want to collect your things.
稍等一下
In a minute.
我们没有时间耽误了
We really shouldn't linger.
我知道  但这么一天下来
I know, but after the day I've had,
我需要喝点比茶水更烈的
I could use something a little stronger than tea.
这些是受害者的账户
Here's the victim's accounts.
能看出这些开支有什么问题吗
You recognize any of these charges?
五金店
Hardware stores.
我的账户上也有很多五金店的交易
There were a lot of those on my accounts too.
还有大量化学品的买入
And bulk purchases of chemicals.
这是警察用来指控我的证据
That's what the cops used as evidence against me.
-供实验室用  -应该是
- Supplies for the labs. - I guess.
还看出别的什么吗
Recognize anything else?
好吧
Okay.
这些是银行方面的证词
These are the bank statements.
-能看出什么吗  -等等
- You recognize anything here? - Wait.
你为什么会有她的照片
Why do you have a picture of her?
这是乔丹・海丝特  她是受害者
That's Jordan Hester. She's the victim.
不不不  她是玛丽
No, no, no, that's Mary.
她是我会计师的接待员
She was the receptionist at my accountant's office.
玛丽?
Mary?
失陪一下
Excuse me a minute.
擦干净之后  赶紧出去
When you're done with the wipe-down, get the hell out,
我找到新的实验室会再和你们联系
and I'll be in touch when I find a new lab.
找和上一间那样带天窗的
Get one with skylights like the last one.
我们加热磷粉时能更好地通风
It's better ventilation for when we heat the phosphorous.
当然可以  什么都行
Yeah, sure, whatever you want.
快点
Let's move!
磷粉是用来制作冰毒的  老大
Phosphorous is used to make meth, "Boss."
而且上一间实验室根本没有天窗
And the last place didn't have any skylights.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我觉得我们弄反了  芬奇
I think we may have gotten this backwards, Finch.
我跟的海丝特不是冒充者
My Hester's not the identity thief,
也就是说  你跟的才是
which means yours is.
弗斯科
是那个女人
我知道了
I know.
出事了吗  哈罗德
Something wrong, Harold?
我不知道你是谁  但你不是老大
I don't know who you are, but you're not the boss.
别傻了  把枪放下
Don't be an idiot. Put the gun down.
老大  老大  警察就在外面
Boss, boss, the cops are outside.
大家尽量多拿点
Everybody grab what they can.
他就是把我揍晕的人
That's the guy who knocked me out.
我们没时间纠缠了
We don't have time for this.
我知道你是真正的乔丹・海丝特
I know you're the real Jordan Hester.
那你就该知道我哪儿也不会去
Then you know I'm not going anywhere.
我好像有点不舒服
I don't think I feel very well.
实际上  我很确定
In fact, I'm certain of it.
我感觉很晕
I feel quite discombobu--
晕  眩
Bobu--bobu--
会过去的  哈罗德
It'll pass, Harold.
别担心  马上  你就会感觉很好的
Don't worry. Pretty soon, you'll feel much better.
告诉我你是谁
Tell me who you are.
现在  我是谁不重要
Who I am doesn't matter right now.
重要的是  我知道你是谁
What matters is, I know who you are.
那我是谁  别过来
Who am I, then? Stay back.
-我会开枪的  -怎么开
- I will shoot you. - How?
保险还开着呢
the safety's still on.
无意冒犯
No offense,
但真不敢相信你居然把这群人骗了这么久
but I'm surprised you fooled these guys as long as you did.
你真觉得毒贩会穿成你这样吗
Is that really how you think a drug dealer dresses?
我知道你是真正的乔丹・海丝特
I know you're the real Jordan Hester.
我知道你的生活被偷走了
I know your life was stolen.
给你  我甚至知道是谁偷的
Here. I even know who stole it.
绑那一个
Do the other one.
那  是谁偷的
Well, who stole it?
先解决当务之急
First things first.
你是如何计划的
What exactly was your plan?
你被指控贩毒
You were accused of being a drug dealer,
所以就决定成为毒贩吗
so then you decided to become one?
没有人会相信我
No one would believe me.
而我又一直很内向
And I was always a bit of an introvert,
很注重隐私
you know, a private person.
是啊  我很熟这类人
Yeah, I know the type.
我从未想到这样会惹祸上身
I never thought that I would be punished for it.
我之前的老板  警察
My old boss, police--
人们一听说你是贩毒的
People hear you're a drug dealer,
就不愿再听你解释了
they stop listening to you.
你有没有陷入最低谷的时候
I mean, have you ever hit bottom?
我不知道自己能陷得多深
I never realized how far down I could go.
过了一阵子  我明白了
After a while, I figured,
如果别人硬要说我是这种坏人
if people keep thinking I'm this bad guy,
我又何必喋喋不休地说服他们我不是呢
why do I keep trying to convince them that I'm not?
有人偷走了你的身份
Someone stole your identity,
所以你决定要偷走他们的
so you decided to steal theirs.
是的  只要拖到能捣毁这间实验室就行
Well, yeah, but only long enough to destroy this lab.
那是硝酸  不是黄樟醚
That's nitric acid, not safrole.
它能腐蚀一切  摧毁这些仪器
It'll melt all this into mush, destroy this equipment.
然后我打算拿走剩下的库存
And then I was going to take the rest of this supply,
大概价值五十万美元
about $1/2 million worth,
以此将那混蛋引到光天化日之下
to lure that bastard out into the open.
然后怎么办  杀了他吗
And then what? Kill him?
我不想杀人
I don't want to kill anybody.
我只想拿回我的身份
I just want my identity back.
好吧
Okay.
这计划真烂
It's a terrible plan.
不过我喜欢  我们行动吧
But I like it, so let's do it.
首先你必须知道的
First thing you need to know,
那个混蛋不是他  而是她
the bastard isn't a he. She's a she.
芬奇  你在吗
Finch, are you there?
确定一定以及肯定
I most certainly am.
你得从那里出来
You need to get out of there.
他并未计划杀了她
He wasn't planning to kill her,
所以一定是她在计划杀了他
So she must still be planning to kill him.
为什么  我从不
Why, I never...
哈罗德?
Harold?
你还好吗
You all right?
-我确信你给我下了毒  -摇头丸
- I believe you've drugged me. - Ecstasy.
我说过  你会感觉很好的
I told you you'd feel better.
我的多巴胺和去甲肾上腺素水平现在是
My dopamine and norepinephrine levels are...
但我清楚这个过程
But if I understand this process,
我就能计算出
I can counter the ef--
你好呀
Well, hello there.
不这样就得开枪
Well, it was either this or shoot you.
我发现化学品
I find chemistry...
效率要高得多
so much more efficient.
芬奇  我这边都搞定了
Finch, I've got this end under control.
我们准备给我们共同的朋友一份惊喜
We're preparing a surprise for our mutual friend.
《我们共同的朋友》  作者查尔斯・狄更斯
Our Mutual Friend, Charles Dickens,
出版于  1864或65年
published...1864, '65.
情节是一桩隐藏身份的案子
The plot turns on a case of concealed identity!
多么讽刺
How ironic.
你有这本书吗
Hey, do you have a copy?
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
芬奇  你还好吗
Finch, are you all right?
好得不能再好了
Never been all right-er.
但我好像被人坑了
But I might have been outfoxed.
芬奇被坑了
Finch outfoxed.
芬奇  你怎么了
Finch, what's going on?
你究竟在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
芬
Fi--
芬奇
Finch?
那是我很好很好的朋友
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, that is my very good friend.
是谁
Who was it?
他是谁  他在哪里
Who is he? Where is he?
无关紧要的地方
Nowhere that matters,
不在实验室里噢
and not in the lab.
不
No.
乔瑟夫  是我
Joseph, it's me.
你必须赶到实验室去  不  现在
You need to get to the lab. No, now.
麻烦比我想象中的大
We've got bigger problems than I thought.
我现在有些事要处理
I'm taking care of things here.
在那里碰头
I'll meet you there.
我喜欢侧过来看你的脸
I like your face sideways.
抱歉了  哈罗德
I'm sorry, Harold.
一定要快  弗斯科
Fast as you can, Fusco.
上城区十二号街851号  芬奇出事了
851 12th Street, the Village. Finch is in trouble.
好的  我上路了
All right, I'm on it.
你服役时的安全级别
You've still got your security clearance
还保留着  警探
from your time in the army, Detective,
所以我能带你进来
So I can show you this.
联调局通常不会启动机密行动
The FBI doesn't run classified ops
除非涉及  国家安全问题
unless there's issues of... National security.
以前是中情局跟我们紧密合作
Used to be the CIA worked closely with us,
后来停止了
then they stopped.
极端行动成了他们的做事准则
Extreme action became the norm.
绑票  偷渡  暗杀
Kidnappings, renditions, assassinations,
更糟的是  我们认为有些他们甚至是
and worse, we think they did some of these things
在美国本土做的
right here in the U.S.
为了启动机密行动
And to run these ops,
他们需要危险的  往往有反社会倾向的人
They needed dangerous, often sociopathic men...
就像你一直追查的家伙
Like the one you've been chasing.
但我们认为  他已经离开了局里
But at some point, we think this man left the agency.
开始的时候  我们无迹可寻
Initially, the pattern was chaotic,
现在已经有了大致的方向
but now a trend has emerged.
我想我们知道他来纽约做什么
We think we know what he's doing here in New York.
做什么呢
And what is that?
我们认为他现在是赏金猎人  价高者得
We think he's selling his services to the highest bidder.
我们遇到过类似的案子  墨西哥特种部队
We've seen it before, Mexican special forces
接手了华瑞兹市的毒品生意
taking over the drug trade in Juarez,
前英国空军特别部队在利比亚兜售血钻
ex-British SAS selling blood diamonds in Liberia...
像他们这种人  一旦退役
Men like that, they're done fighting,
社会上没有他们的容身之地
there's no place for them in society,
于是就将他们逼成了危险分子
which makes them very dangerous.
我们相信他跟某个
We believe he's been working with one
有组织犯罪团伙合作
of the organized crime syndicates,
尤其是一个叫以利亚的人
Specifically a man named Elias.
你觉得他在为以利亚卖命吗
You think he's working for Elias?
我们安插在俄罗斯黑手党的线人汇报
One of our contacts in the Russian mob told us
他把他们派去追杀以利亚的人全放倒了
he took out a team they sent to kill Elias.
现在中情局已经在着手处理这件事了
Now the CIA is already trying to clean up this mess.
我们知道你一直跟斯诺特工有联系
We know that you've been contacted by this man, agent Snow.
我们相信他就是中情局负责
We believe that he's the man the agency uses
为境内特别行动提供掩护的人
to sweep these domestic ops under the rug.
告诉我
Tell me...
局里对这个为什么感兴趣
what's the bureau's interest in this?
你又为什么感兴趣
What's your interest?
想跟中情局搞鬼吗
You want to put one over on the CIA?
没错  我要揭露中情局的行径
Yes, I want to expose the CIA for what it's become,
但最主要的  我想将他绳之于法
but...mainly, I want to catch him.
我们不能让那群政府的恶棍打手
We can't have rogue government hit men
插手国内事务
operating on domestic soil.
很显然你也这么认为
Obviously you feel the same.
所以你才小心地追查他
That's why you've been so vigilant in pursuing him.
-可惜没收获  -快了
- Without much luck. - So far.
你一直单枪匹马作战
But you've been working alone.
现在你有局里做后盾
Now you'll have the bureau's support.
我们得翻查之前的案子
We're going back to all the old cases,
重新调查目击者  审视证物
reinterviewing witnesses, looking at physical evidence,
除了你的报告之外
So beyond your report,
还有别的什么线索吗
is there anything else you can share with us?
没什么了
Nothing comes to mind.
不过  有的话我会通知你
But, I'll keep you informed.
放心  警官
Rest assured, detective.
我们会抓到他
We'll find him.
-你一个人  -什么
- You alone? - What?
你好  警官  刚好吃晚饭
Hello, detective, just in time for dinner.
随便坐  快好了
Have a seat. Almost ready.
快餐
Fast food.
很不好
Very bad.
-那是什么  -她做给我的
- What is that? - She made it for me.
红烧的噢
It's some kind of flambe.
等下  等下  还没好呢
Wait, wait, wait, it's not quite ready.
来吧  先把你弄出去
Come on, let's get you out of here.
好哒
Okay.
这边  这边
This way, this way.
我找到他了
I got him.
很好  谢谢  莱奈尔
Good. Thanks, Lionel.
我们搞定后再打给你
I'll call you as soon as we're clear.
我们走
Let's go.
别动
Don't move!
把包放下  把包放下
Drop the bags. Drop the bags.
你好  海丝特先生
Hello, Mr. Hester.
你真以为自己能接手我的生意吗
Did you really think you could take over my operation?
你来了  不是吗
Well, you're here, aren't you?
说得好
Touche.
我在考虑把你的名字多用一段时间
I'm thinking of keeping your name a little longer.
毕竟
After all...
我做乔丹・海丝特可比你做得好
I'm a better Jordan Hester than you've ever been.
把他们干掉
Get rid of them.
这里的化学品足够处理尸体了
More than enough chemicals in here to deal with the bodies.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我有很重要的东西要给你看
I've got something important to show you.
是吗  什么
Yeah, yeah, what's that?
盐酸
Hydrochloric acid.
你不想我脱手吧
You don't want me to drop this.
你说谎
You're lying.
是吗
Yeah?
别紧张
Relax.
只是水罢了
It's just water.
该结束这一切了  不是吗
Time to finish this, don't you think?
快关了
Hey, knock it off.
我们要去哪儿
Where are we going?
我要去抓坏人
I'm gonna take down some bad guys.
你待在车里别动
You're gonna stay in the car.
给你
Here.
我要这个干什么
What am I supposed to do with this?
我发现两个乔丹・海丝特之间的联系了
I found what connects the two Jordan Hesters:
报税事务所优惠  同一个会计师
A discount tax prep chain, same accountant.
你要帮我逮到他
You're going to help me track him down.
给你  知道怎么用吗
Here. Know how to work this?
你想黑进五角大楼吗
You wanna hack the Pentagon?
我们非要在这儿见面吗
We had to meet here?
别紧张  理查德
Relax, Richard.
陪客户用餐可以销账
Dinners with clients are a write-off.
你应该知道的
You should know that.
我不能再做了  玛丽
I can't keep doing this, Mary.
我可能会丢饭碗
I could lose my job.
给我想要的
You give me what I want,
不然  你丢的远不止是饭碗
or you're going to lose a lot more than your job.
现在  我下一个要扮谁
Now, who do I get to be next?
你说过这次想要女人  是吧
You said a woman this time, right?
男人太有报复心了
Well, men tend to hold a grudge.
不如试试这个
Try this one instead.
你也不叫玛丽
Your name's not Mary either.
而叫塔拉
It's Tara.
你可以滚了
You can run along.
入案档案照不错
Nice mug shot.
前科档案同样令人赞叹
Impressive rap sheet too.
商店行窃  伪造支票  保险诈骗
Arrests for shoplifting, forging checks, insurance fraud.
你23岁就已经声名狼藉了
Torched your own name by the time you were 23.
现在如何
What now?
你要杀了我
You gonna kill me?
某一刻  我是有这么想过
For a while, I thought I might have it in me.
不过  我只是在假扮你  不是吗
But then, I was just playing you, wasn't I?
对了  你这个乔丹・海丝特做得很糟糕
For the record, you make a terrible Jordan Hester.
她在那里
There she is.
塔拉・韦兰德
Tara Verlander.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
我们稍后再指出你的罪名
We'll get to the charges later.
要清点你的罪名真得花点时间
Gonna take some time to sort this out.
谢谢你
Thank you...
谢谢你救回了我的生活
For giving me my life back.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你怎么查到她之前的入案档案的
How did you track down her old mug shot?
小心头
Watch your head.
警察的工作  我偶尔也要做的
Police work. Even I do it on occasion.
我挺惊讶你居然不出面领功
I'm surprised you didn't want the collar.
太高调了
Too high-profile.
而且我想HR也有分一杯羹
Plus I think HR's taking a cut of her operation.
你更喜欢哪个  好警察  还是坏警察
Which do you like better, good cop or bad cop?
你说呢
You tell me.
我在HR卧底  还是跟你办案
Am I under with HR, or am I working cases with you?
以后告诉你
I'll let you know.
未知号码
释放犯人
Releasing prisoner.
-你自由了  -谢谢
- You are a free man. - Thank you.
回家见你的宝贝女儿吧
Now get home to your little girl.
我没告诉你我有这么多藏书
I didn't tell you that I have so many books.
几个小时后毒品就会排泄出去了
It'll be out of your system in a few hours.
不过你得该喝下这些
But you should really drink this,
免得脱水
so you don't get dehydrated.
你要走吗
You're leaving?
不  我会留在附近  保护你
No, I'll stick around, keep an eye on you.
你该睡会儿了
You should really get some sleep.
你不想谈谈吗
You don't want to talk?
明天早上你会后悔的
You might regret it in the morning.
你很注重隐私  记得吗
You're a very private person, remember?
拜托  问我什么都行
Come on. Ask me anything.
晚安  哈罗德
Good night, Harold.
晚安  奈森
Good night, Nathan.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第18集
Person of Interest S01E18 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-